Guide to the Maud Slye Papers 1910s-1930s
University of Chicago Library
Slye, Maud. Papers
1910s-1930s
27 linear feet (55 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Maud Slye (1869-1954), University of Chicago pathologist and cancer specialist. The Maud Slye papers consist of research records, published and unpublished manuscripts, and correspondence.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Maud Slye was born in Minneapolis in 1869. Many published sources give her birth date as February 8, 1879, but U.S. Census records indicate that she was born in 1869; it may be that claimed the later birth date to avoid mandatory retirement. In 1895, Slye entered the University of Chicago as an undergraduate student and worked as secretary for President William Rainey Harper to support herself. Following a breakdown brought on by the strain of full-time work and study, Slye relocated to the East Coast and received her A.B. degree from Brown University in 1899. She taught at Rhode Island State Normal School until 1905, and in 1908 returned to the University of Chicago as a graduate assistant to Professor Charles Otis Whitman.
Slye began her pioneering research on cancer heredity in mice soon after her arrival in Chicago, and in 1911 joined the University's newly opened Sprague Memorial Institute. In 1919 she was appointed director of the Cancer Laboratory at the University of Chicago, and in 1926 was promoted to associate professor of pathology, a position she held until her retirement in 1944. Slye performed her research with only minimal financial support from the University, often paying for mouse food and other supplies out of her personal stipend. Her first research assistant, Harriet Holmes, worked without pay.
Slye faced criticism from other pathologists and researchers for her contention that heredity played a key role in susceptibility to cancer; her research challenged prevailing notions of cancer as being at least partly caused by contagions. Although her hypotheses about heredity were later shown to be a simplification of the complex role genetics play in cancer susceptibility, her studies were crucial in establishing heredity as a key area for cancer research.
Slye sometimes had to battle gender-based stereotypes and criticism, including questions from the press about whether she was “afraid” of her mice and a cruel rumor that circulated for a time in the cancer research field, charging that she had refused to share her research results with scientists from the New York Institute for Cancer Research and had cried when questioned about her findings. Nevertheless, Slye was recognized for her work, receiving a gold medal from the American Medical Society in 1914 and another from the American Radiological Association in 1922. She was also awarded the Ricketts Prize from the University of Chicago in 1915 and an honorary doctorate from Brown University in 1937.
In addition to her scientific work, Slye published two volumes of poetry, Songs and Solaces (1934) and I in the Wind (1936). She died in Chicago in 1954.
Scope Note
The Maud Slye papers contain extensive records from Slye's research on cancer in mice. Also included are several articles by Slye about her research findings and some professional correspondence.
Series I contains records organized by reference to the mice's cage numbers. Series II contains schematic outlines that track generations of mice by genetic strain. The records in Series III catalog types and locations of tumors in the mice as well as other list other ailments. Series IV contains autopsy and histology records. Series V contains notes, articles by Slye and others, and correspondence. Series VI contains an oversize schematic outline chart.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Whitman, Charles Otis. Collection
Subject Headings
Slye, Maud, 1879-1954; University of Chicago -- History; Cancer -- Genetic aspects; Cancer -- Research; Women scientists
INVENTORY
- Series I: Cage Records
  - Cage Records 1 -9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 10 - 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 20 - 26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 28 - 29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 30 - 32 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 33 - 39 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 40 - 49 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 50 - 54 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 55 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 56 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 57 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 58 - 59 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 60 - 69 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 70 - 76 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 77 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 78 - 79 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 80 - 83 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 84 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 85y (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records 85y/y17 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Cage Records 85y/y8 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 85y/y17 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 85y/y (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 85y/y7 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 85y/y7 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 85y/y7 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 85y/y7 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 85y/y7 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 85y/y (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 85y2/young (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 85y2/y2Ø (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 85a (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 86 - 89 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 90 - 99 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 100 - 109 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 110 - 119 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 120 - 129 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 130 - 133ay3 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 133ay4 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 133ay5 - ay15 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records 133ay16 - ay19 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cage Records 133ay20 - ay29 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 133ay30 - ay39 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 133a/a -c (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 135 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 136 - 139 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 140 - 144 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 145 - 145♂ (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 145* - 145y (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 145a-a// (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 145a/// (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 146-147 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 148 - 148/416 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 148/441T - 148/621 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 148* - 148*/84a (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 148*/84a (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 148*/84ay (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 148*/123 - 148*/441T (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 148*/461c5/y (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 148*/547 - 148*Jap.D. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 148*y (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records 148*yy2 - *yy4 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Cage Records 148*yy5 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Cage Records 148*yy6 - *yy15 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 148*1 - ** - T (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 148a - etc. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 85 - * - T (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 85/405 2T Series (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 1483 - 1483y2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 1483y3 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 1483y4 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 148Ø - 148= (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 149 - 149/416x/x (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 149/541 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 150-160 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 160-164b (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 164c-164d (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 164c (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 164e/e (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 164f-1642 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 165-169 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 170-179 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 180-182ay3 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 182ay4-ay11 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 182ay12 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 183-189 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 190-199 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 200-209 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 210-219 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 220-229 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records 230-239 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Cage Records 240-249 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Cage Records 250-259 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Cage Records 260-269 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Cage Records 270-279 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Cage Records 290-299 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cage Records 300 - 309 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 310 - 319 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 320 - 326 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 280 - 284* (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 284W (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 284ww - wwy (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 284wwyy (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 285 - 289 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 327 - H - 327H/145 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 327H/148*/84ay (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 327H/150 - 327H/800 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 327H/T (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 327Hy - HP (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 328 - 329 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 330-339 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 340-349 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 350 - 359 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 360 - 369 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 370 - 379 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 380 - 389 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records 390 - 399 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Cage Records 400 - 402 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cage Records 402* - ** (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Cage Records 402T (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Cage Records 402B (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Cage Records 402b/Red (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Cage Records 402b/Red1 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Cage Records 402b/Red1 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Cage Records 402b/r - 404 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 405 - 405b/wg (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 405b/wg - b/wgyy (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 405b/wg albs. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 406 - 409 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 410 - 415 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 416/275 - 416/402 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 416/406 - * - *y*y1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 416/405*y*y2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 416/405*y*y3 - 8 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 416/405*y*y9 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 416/405*y** - 416/405y (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 416d/y - d/y1 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 416dy17 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 416dy18 - etc. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 416d/y - d/y1 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 416 d/y 1/1 - 1/2 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 416d/y2 - d/y9 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 416/416 - 416w/r (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 416* - 416T (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 416y - y/y (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 416B1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 416R - R* (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 416R/b1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 416Rb (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 416R/b (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 416R (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 416a (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 416d (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 416dy - dy16 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 416d1 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 416H (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 416I (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 417 - 419 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 416 B, b, C (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 430 - 439 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 440 - 441 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 442 - 443 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records 444 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Cage Records 445 - 449 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Cage Records 450 - 459 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Cage Records 460 - 461/700my10 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Cage Records 461/700my11 - etc. (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Cage Records 420 - 429 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 461* - 461b (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 461C (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 461H - etc. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 462 - 464 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 465 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 466 - 469 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 470 - 479 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 490 - 499 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 500 - 509 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 510 - 518 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 519 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 520 - 523 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 524 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 530 - 539 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 540 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 541 - 541/807/wy (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 541T (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 542 - 546 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 547 - 549 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 550 - 559 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 560 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 561 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 562 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 563 - 565 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 566 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 567 - 569 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 570 - 579 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 580 - 589 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 590 - 598 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 600 - 601y/y (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 601a1b - 609 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 612 - 614, 619 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 621 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 630 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 641, 642, 647 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 650, 652 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 670 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 680 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records 690 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Cage Records 706 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Cage Records 706 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Cage Records 700 - 705 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 710 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 720 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 800 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 810 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 820 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 840 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 900 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 910 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 920 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 940 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 950 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 2000D/A (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 2222♀ - ♂ - B1 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 2222/3333Iy (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 2222/3333Iy (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 2222/3333Iy (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 2222 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 2222/3333Iy ♀Red y (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Cage Records 2222/3333Iy ♀Red/Sm (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records 3333I (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Cage Records 3333Iyalb1 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Cage Records 3333Iyalbs (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Cage Records 3333Iy1 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Cage Records 3333Iy2 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Cage Records 3333Iy2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 3333Iy2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 3333Iyy (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 3333Iy3 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 3333Iy3 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 3333IRed (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 3333II/3333Iy1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 3333II (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 3333IIy (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 3333II (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 4000 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 5000 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records 6000 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 7000 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records 8000 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 9000 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records B/MBx (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records M/BBx (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records M/B (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records M/B (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8II (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8II (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records B/M (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8II (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8II (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8II, BOX 14 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8I (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8II (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8II (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 85/405/WQy8II (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records WQy8/85/405II (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records WQy8/85/405III (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records WQ/7/WQ (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records WQy8/85/405 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records WQy8/85/405II (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records WQy/284W/416y (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records WQ/284W/416y (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records WQ/284W/416y (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records WQ/284W/416y (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records WQ/284W/416y (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records WQ/284W/416y (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records WQ/284W/416y (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 7y2/3/7/WQA (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 7y2/3/7II (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 7y2/3/7I (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records W2y3 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records W2y4 - y7 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records WQy8 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records W2y9 - y14 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records W2y15 - y19 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records W2y20 - y29 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records WQy30 - y39 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records WM (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records WR (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records S (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records Ames, Iowa and Billings (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records WJ (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records H.M./712 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records WX (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records Wy (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records XXX (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 7/WQ(1) + (2) (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records 7/WQ (4) + (5) (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records 7/WQ (3) (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - 7/WQ (6) (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Cage Records W2/7 (1), (2) + (6) (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records W2/7 (3) (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records WQ (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records W2y - W2y/133 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records W2y/284W/416y y2 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records W2y/284W/416y y2/y3* - *y (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records y2/y3*yy - *yy3 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records y2/y3*yy4 - *yy10 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records y2/y3*yy11 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records y2/y3*yy12 - *yy17 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records WQy/284w/416y y3 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records WQy/441T/182a (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records W2y* & yT (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records W2y1 - y2 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records N/MI (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records N/MII (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records N/MIII (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records W2/7(5) (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records WQ/7 (5) 2 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records W2/y (4) (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records WQ/7 (3) I (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records R1 - 2 - 3 - 4 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records Line 1, Parents and F1 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records Line 1, Br. 1 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records Line 1, Br. II (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records Line 1, Br. III (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records Line 1, Br. IV (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records Line 1, Br. V (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records Line 1, Br. VI (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records Xs between Br. III, etc. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records Lines 2, 4, 6, 8, 10 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records 3/7I & II (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Cage Records Line 3, BR. IA & B (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Cage Records 3yII (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Cage Records 3yIII (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Cage Records Line 5, parents, g1, Br. I & II (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Cage Records Line 5 g1 III & IV (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records Line 5 y1 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 7y1 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records 7y2/W2y8 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records 7y2g3♀1g4♀♂ (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 7y2g3 ♀1/♂1 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records 7y3 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 7yx1y4 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records 7yx1y4 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records 7yx1y4/9 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records 9yIy2g2♀/♂ (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records 9yII (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Cage Records 9y1 - y2 & y4 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Cage Records 9 - g2 - yI (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Cage Records w2/9 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Cage Records w2/8888 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Cage Records 8888/w2 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Cage Records w2/9 patterns (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Cage Records 9/w2 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Cage Records WQy8y♀2♀/♂1 Line Bg1 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Cage Records WQy8y♀2 ♀/♂1 Line A (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Cage Records WQy8y♀2♀/♂1 Line A (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Cage Records W (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Cage Records Q (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Cage Records WI - V (Box 20, Folder 14)
- Series II: Schematic Outlines of Genetic Strains
  - Schematic Outline Q (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Schematic Outline WQy8 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Schematic Outline WQy8y (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Schematic Outline (7y2x3 - 7)xWQA (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Schematic Outline 7XWQ (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Schematic Outline WQx7 (3) (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Schematic Outlines WQx7 (1), (2), & (6) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Schematic Outline 9xWQ (1) (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Schematic Outline (WQ-7)xWQ (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Schematic Outline Line 1 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Schematic Outline Line 3 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Schematic Outline Line 5 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Schematic Outline Line 7 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Schematic Outline Line 9 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Schematic Outline 3x7 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Schematic Outline (7x1)x9 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Schematic Outlines 7y2x (3 - 7) (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Schematic Outlines 7y2x (3 - 7) (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Schematic Outline 7x1 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Schematic Outline R3 & R4 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Schematic Outline 7y2xWQy8I (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Schematic Outline 7y2xWQy8I & IV (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Schematic Outline Parents of MXB & BXM (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Schematic Outline BxM Inbred (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Schematic Outline BXMBX par♂ (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Schematic Outline MxB (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Schematic Outline NxCI (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Schematic Outline NxCII (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Schematic Outline NxCII (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Schematic Outline NxCIII (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Schematic Outline 2222B1 A & B (Box 22, Folder 20)
- Series III: Cancer and Other Illness Records
  - First 10,000 - Summaries A-D (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Mammary gland list (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Mammary gland tumor list (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Mammary gland tumor list, 2nd 10,000 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - General statistics, vol I (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - General statistics, II (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - General cancer list, vol III (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - General cancer list, vol IV (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - General cancer list, vol V (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - General cancer list, vol VI (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - General cancer list, vol VII (Box 24, Folder 2)